<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Yarmoq</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2020-02-22T17:05:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Assembling my Floppy Emu from Big Mess O' Wires</title><link href="2020/02/22/assembling-my-floppy-emu-from-big-mess-o-wires/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-22T17:05:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-22T17:05:00-05:00</updated><author><name>loai</name></author><id>tag:None,2020-02-22:2020/02/22/assembling-my-floppy-emu-from-big-mess-o-wires/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back on February 1st I ordered a &lt;a href="https://www.bigmessowires.com/floppy-emu/"&gt;Floppy Emu&lt;/a&gt; from Big Mess O' Wires. The Floppy Emu emulates a floppy disk drive. Floppy disk images can be stored on the SD card and mounted from the Floppy Emu itself. This makes it a lot easier to transfer and use software …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back on February 1st I ordered a &lt;a href="https://www.bigmessowires.com/floppy-emu/"&gt;Floppy Emu&lt;/a&gt; from Big Mess O' Wires. The Floppy Emu emulates a floppy disk drive. Floppy disk images can be stored on the SD card and mounted from the Floppy Emu itself. This makes it a lot easier to transfer and use software on the Mac and the Apple II.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan is to use it with my Apple II computers and my olders Macs, most importantly, my &lt;a href="https://gtia.com/2020/01/30/i-now-have-128mb-of-ram-in-my-se-30-/"&gt;128MB Macintosh SE/30&lt;/a&gt;. Shipping was pretty fast, and after a quick flash to install the Macintosh Floppy Drive firmware, I was playing &lt;em&gt;Prince of Persia&lt;/em&gt; on my SE/30. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ordered the full set up for $139, including the case and the SD card with Apple II and Mac software. The drive worked great. Unfortunately, in my haste, I dropped the Floppy Emu. Of course, I hadn't assembled the case. Well, the Floppy Emu came through with flying colors. The SD card did not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Broken SD Card" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/BrokenSD-2020-02-22-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I assembled the case. It was a quick assembly, it took longer to get the adhesive paper off of the parts than it did to assemble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="So much paper" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/FloppyEmuAssembly-2020-02-22-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I have a completed Floppy Emu! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Assembled Floppy Emu" src="https://cdn.gtia.com/pics/2020/FinishedFloppyEmu-2020-02-22-800x.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next task is to start downloading software to play around with on my Mac. I think I'm going to set up two SD cards, one with Apple II software &amp;amp; the Apple II firmware, the other with Mac software &amp;amp; Mac firmware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use older Apple computers, the &lt;a href="https://www.bigmessowires.com/floppy-emu/"&gt;Floppy Emu&lt;/a&gt; is a must purchase.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Hardware"></category><category term="bmow"></category><category term="apple"></category><category term="mac"></category><category term="ii"></category></entry></feed>